Well, I'll be involved in the search
committee. Um, as we said in the
announcement, uh, we're going to do a
national search, both internal and
external candidates to consider. Uh, we
have a search firm, Russell Reynolds,
working with us. Um, they've been mostly
focusing on identifying external
candidates at this point, but they'll
also, uh, review all the internal
candidates, and we'll start meeting with
them probably in earnest in April to
kind of go through the lay of the land,
who's out there. Um we'll do some
initial screening of um candidates. Um
and then probably have a full interview
panel that if you include me and Sheila
um Chris Beielman, I think Bill Ford's
going to get involved um and Lindsay
Stagen, our uh chief people officer. And
at the very end, I want to give um you
know, Brad and Dan a chance to weigh in
on the on the process and the person. So
in terms of what I'm looking for, I'm
looking for the best person to lead the
Lions. Um, ideally somebody who's, you
know, got the right kind of executive
presence and leadership skills. Um, you
know, some COO or CEO experience running
a big organization. Um, doesn't
necessarily have to be somebody with
football experience, but that would, you
know, be an advantage if it works out.
Um, and we've got a lot of really
interesting people that have raised
their hands, so we'll see where it goes.
>> What made this the uh right time for you
to hang it up?
>> Just, you know, I've been thinking about
it for a couple years. Um I I you know
mentioned a couple times I would have
liked to have gone out last year after a
parade you know after the 15-2
you know season number one seed but uh
that didn't work out. So I said let's
you know come back and try it one more
time. Um I'm going to be 66 this summer.
There's a you know time to move on and a
time to focus on the rest of whatever
time I have with my family and friends.
And it just feels right. I think
organization is is ready for you know
transition. Uh we've got good leadership
in place, a really good football team in
place and um it seems like the right
time to hand the baton.
>> I'm curious. The league has changed so
much since you have taken over this job.
You know, we talked about the
international game, league day game,
those stuff.
>> Do you have any kind of I don't know
what call bold predictions, but is there
anything that you is on the horizon the
league that you're particularly
intrigued in whether it be trends or
something like that?
Um, I I think the things is, you know, a
couple things you hit on international
play. I think that'll continue to
expand. Um, it's a CBA issue, but I
think that, you know, eventually they'd
like to get to probably one
international game every week. You know,
16 games, everybody play at least one
per year, maybe maybe two in some cases.
Um, certainly streaming is a big change.
Um, I think it was initially kind of
slow to adapt. the first year Amazon
people had a hard time finding where you
find Prime on your TV, but you know this
year they've now surpassed the ratings
of Fox the last year that Fox had the
Thursday night broadcast. Uh the Netflix
numbers are kind of through the roof for
the Christmas Day game. So I think you
know balancing you know where the
younger fan wants to watch games versus
you know the traditional fans. Um so
that's a big change. I think one of the
other things we talked a little bit
about this morning is the whole changing
landscape of college football and what
that may do to you know people that are
coming into the NFL that are older and
we talked about Indiana you know having
a team that was almost as old as the
Packers in terms of age and so when
you're drafting a 24 year old or a
25year-old their second contract they're
30 you know what's that going to do to
how you plan for the you know the second
contract and you know how much you want
to invest in a a 25y old so
>> you know GMs and Indie for that matter
here too is just about that concept of
like it being an older league people
coming into
>> what's what is the consensus or what is
the thought of people
>> I don't know if there is a consensus
it's just something to be watching and
you know the ripple effects of you know
now you know some of the best high
school players are getting agents and
getting NIL deals and then you know you
go into you know a college environment
where you're getting a lot of money to
play college football and the financial
incentive to go to the NFL is less than
it once was. Um, you know, historically
a lot of the first round picks have been
underclassmen and now it's, you know,
unlikely to be underassman. They're
probably being incented to stay. Unless
you're going to be a top 10 pick,
there's not a financial windfall waiting
for you, uh, if you're a big-time
college player. So, I don't know if
there is a solution, but it's something
we're talking about and something to be
aware of. Um, and I think, you know,
it'll have a way of figuring itself out.
I mean, right now, maybe everybody will
try and copy Indiana and we'll see if
that doesn't work in a couple years and
maybe go back to basketball. 10 years
ago, it was the one and done and if you
didn't have that, you couldn't compete.
And now it's and basketball's kind of
shifted back the other way, too. So,
we'll see what happens, but it's
something to watch. Um, and I think for
the NFL, the issue is what do you what
do you do with a 24 25 year old rookie
in terms of investment in them versus
waiting for, you know, a second contract
when they're 30 and 35 or 30 or 31? So,
>> speaking of Oh, sorry. Go ahead. Go
>> ahead. Just speaking of league changes,
this the 18 game schedule is something
that continues to get talked about. Like
what are the team's thoughts on that or
like what are the concessions that kind
of need to be met in the middle to make
that happen? Well, that you know that's
a CBA issue and I think there's a lot of
time between here and and then and I
think there's a lot of things that would
have to get sorted out in terms of buys
and when the schedules are put together
and you know if you add in you know 16
international games and an 18 game
schedule and the travel and all those
things. Um it obviously creates a window
for a TV deal that doesn't exist today
and everybody benefits from that if if
um there's additional revenue but I
think you know between now and then
there's a lot to figure out and I would
say it's you know an issue that is
talked about but relatively minor
compared to other things that we're
talking about ask you kind of a cap cash
question. Um
>> we obviously look through things at the
lens of cap because that's how the
roster is constructed. you spend a lot
more time thinking about cash in cash
out. And so when you do these big
restructures and Jared Goff gets the
golf check in the facility like
>> um what is kind of the the state of the
team from a cash perspective? What are
the challenges of of managing some of
those those bigger cash out payments?
>> Well, we look at it both ways. Um, you
know, obviously, you know, the cap has
the ability to have, you know, some
opportunities to manipulate it by, you
know, converting roster bonus or signing
bonus or converting P5 to one or the
other, adding void years. Um, but at the
end of the day, over a period of time,
the cash and cap should be pretty close
to equal. And so, we spent a lot of time
figuring out if we're going to be over
the cap this year, you know, where do we
get that back? And if we're going to be
under the cap this year, where do we
plan to overspend? um there really isn't
any per se cash constraints that we
don't have the money to do what we want
to do. You just don't want to get so
overextended that you know eventually
you're going to have to have a major
reset in your roster because you're so
far over the cap.
>> Um and on the other side you don't want
to be so you know frugal that you can't
compete. So it's kind of a balancing
act. Um most of the league right now is
running a little bit over 100% of the
cap in cash spend. Um which is you know
a relatively new trend. And I think it
really started after the co year when
everybody had to kind of reset their
contracts to get under the cap. Um and
then it's kind of continued to spill
forward. But um you know I look at the
cap and the cash is kind of an equal
constraint and you know try to manage
them together not in any one year but
over like a three to five year period of
time.
>> Mindset organization.
>> Thanks for coming.
>> I want to speak to the mindset of
organization right now. Obviously last
year was a disappointing season, but
when you look at what gives you guys the
confidence that you know Super Bowl
window hasn't passed, like the steps you
guys taken to bounce back to make, you
guys haven't been in this position for a
while, but just the mindset organization
window.
Well, I think we have a, you know,
tremendous coach and we have a
tremendous GM and we have a great
foundation of players, um, that are all
relatively still young in their career.
And, you know, we we obviously we're not
happy with the way the season ended last
year. Uh, injuries are never an excuse,
but eventually we have to have a year
where we don't have more than other
teams. Um, and I think, you know, some
tweaks to the coaching staff, um, by
getting younger on the offensive line
with some of the moves that we made. Um,
and keeping as many of our great
foundational players as we can under
contract. Um, I don't know that too many
teams would trade rosters with us when
you look at us top to bottom. And I
think that we've got elite players at
some of the most important positions.
You know, Pane Su, Ammon, Ra St. Brown,
Hutch. I mean, there's a lot of teams
that would trade for, you know, that
Leaporta at tight end and Gibbs at
running back, G at quarterback. So, you
put it all together, I think that we've
got a a team that can compete. Um, not
to compare, but I don't think too many
people are assuming that the windows
closed on the Chiefs and they only won
six games last year. I mean, so it can
it can, you know, come back just as fast
as it it looked the other way. But, I'm
very confident and we got, you know,
eight draft picks this year. Part of the
reason Brad's not here is he's back
still fine-tuning the draft. Um, seven
picks, uh, yeah, six or seven picks on
Saturday, which is, you know,
opportunity to fill the back of the
roster with younger players. Um, so I
think we've got a plan in place. We've
got a roster that's ready to compete for
a long time.
>> Injury stuff. I know I asked you last
year, you said just kind of a product of
the physical violence style that you
guys like to play.
>> After a second year, have you revisited
that at all?
>> We're looking at everything. And I I
said that I did a you know interview
with Dan Miller earlier today that you
know one of the advantages I guess of a
year that is a disappointment is it
forces you to look inward and really
examine everything and we're trying to
look at every possible reason that
injuries occur. Is it how we practice?
Is it how we play? Is it how we train?
It's how we you know provide nutrition
to the players and how many of them are
preventable versus how many of them are
just bad luck and and really analyze it.
And you know Dan mentioned yesterday
we're not doing joint practices this
year. he's kind of rethought the benefit
of those. Um, but we're not going to
change how we play. We're going to be an
aggressive, you know, quote unquote
violent defense, rally to the ball. Um,
and that could lead to the occasional
injury that maybe is, you know,
different than other team, but it also
leads to a lot of advantages.
>> I want to ask about this Frank Ragnel
thing that's out there today. I want to
ask kind of two parts here. How much
time do you invest looking at how other
teams handle these situations? And then
you know it given the way that the
Calvin situation and how long that kind
of was fractured um do you do you think
about the optics of it at all and I
guess as a maybe a black eye to the
organization?
>> Um I don't really have much more to say
than I've said other than I'll I'll just
say I I really don't spend too much time
looking at what other teams do and I
don't imagine they spend too much time
looking at what we do. We have to do
what's right, you know, for our
organization. And if I worried about
optics, you know, you wouldn't do a lot
of things, but I'm I'm very comfortable
with where we are and every situation's
been handled separately and differently.
And I don't have anything else to say on
that. So,
>> are you surprised? I mean, just to
follow, are you surprised with the push
back or feedback you or you've been in
tune with, you know, what fans are
saying?
>> I'm never surprised by anything. So, no.
What can you uh tell us about the
laboratory jerseys that you guys got
coming up?
>> Um they're very cool. Um you know,
different but within the you kind of the
realm of our current um uniform pallet
and um I don't even know exactly when
they're going to be rolled out. I think
sometime you know drafter or between
draft and the training camp. U I don't
know when we're going to wear them
because I don't know the schedule yet.
you have to wear them against one of
your division rivals at a home game. So,
it'll depend on how the schedule comes
together, but uh I think the fans are
going to like it and um it's it's
different, but uh you know, kind of a
cool factor.
>> Was there a directive on how to design
those or like what they were looking for
specifically or you had some freedom
there? Uh there there was a partnership
between us, the league and Nike and you
there was a series of iterations of you
know ideas that were interesting to us
and ideas that were interesting to them
and we kind of went back and forth and
settled on where we landed. Um so it's a
partnership but with you know creative
people that were not and they are uh and
it worked out I think really in a in a
cool spot.
>> How involved have you been in Germany
event planning at all?
>> Uh a little bit. But I mean, the main
thing I was involved in was kind of
campaigning. If we're going to play
internationally, I'd rather play in
Germany because of the marketing rights
we have there and and Saints popularity.
I know a lot of other teams wanted to
play in Germany. There's a number of of
teams that have marketing rights there.
So, I was happy that it worked out that
we got that market versus, you know, one
of the other ones that we could have
gone to. Um, we just sent a group over
there a couple weeks ago to kind of get
the lay of the land on where we might do
some client entertainment events and
those kind of things. And then we have
another group going over in a couple
weeks that are more on the football
side, looking at, you know, practice
facilities, hotels, etc. Uh, but we've
got some marketing ideas uh that we're
putting into our budget. Um, we're going
to treat it, you know, like a pretty big
deal, you know, from a fan experience
standpoint. Um, I'd like to know exactly
when the game's going to be played and
exactly who we're playing. That that
might help, which I don't know either of
those things yet. Um, but uh once we get
all that figured out, then we can ramp
up some of our planning. More
specifically,
>> the Vikings did that thing last year
where they played backto-back
international games. I think Falcons
have one in there in a way of home for
you. Do you think there's any chance you
guys have double dip internationally
next year?
>> Um, I would never say never, Justin, but
no one's brought it up to me, so I'm
hoping they would have brought it up to
me by now if that was going to happen.
Um, so I don't think that's likely. Is
there anything you're pushing for like a
buy after the national
specific?
>> Well, I'll be candid with you. The one
thing I did push for was to not have the
Thursday to Thursday after Thanksgiving.
>> Um, yeah, assuming, you know, this, you
know, international game in Munich, you
know, might be in November. I think the
games in Germany have been in been in
November. And then to think about flying
back, playing a game, playing
Thanksgiving, then playing the Thursday
afterwards. Uh it's really tough on the
the players and travel. So that's the
one thing I've requested. Um and
hopefully I've made my case on that. The
downside is we played that game two
years in a row and it's been the number
one and number two rated game on Amazon.
So um I've got that fact working against
me. But
>> how does the by-week work with that?
Because I think early on it felt like
every international team got a by-week
and then it seemed like the maybe the
league was offering an option. Is that
something where they seek your input
just given the strain?
>> You know, they've talked about it's not
any longer guaranteed that you'll get
the buy after the international game.
Um, and we're in a little bit of an odd
situation with the, you know, game
likely in November and Thanksgiving. So,
I don't know what our buy treatment will
be. Uh, but I think it's unlikely that
we'll get it the week right after the
game.
>> What do you consider to be the highs and
lows of your tenure?
This is the low meeting with you guys
last time.
>> Yeah. Um, okay. Sorry. That's done.
>> Um, the, you know, the highs, you know,
certainly are, you know, winning the
division back to back. Um, you know,
that Los Angeles Rams playoff game and
the environment and the euphoria of, you
know, winning a home playoff game was
great. Um, I think you know taking a
chance on Dan and Brad and you hiring
two guys that had never done the job
before, never worked together, but
believing that we had the right people
for Detroit. You know, that's a a big
high. Um, I think, you know, some of the
lows, you know, just, you know, early
years we struggled, didn't, you know,
kind of get things figured out as I
would have, you know, as soon as I would
have liked to. The COVID year was really
tough. you know, thinking back on that
and some of the things that we did
during COVID and, you know, believing
all the the science around the vaccine
and mask and testing and those things.
Uh, but at the time that was an unknown,
you know, chartered unchartered area.
So, um, but I would say over in all, you
know, the last several years have kind
of trumped the first couple years in
terms of the the success and where
we're, you know, positioned, I think,
for continued success.
Dan has said a few times this offseason
that kind of gets back wants to get back
to that 2022 mentality like you had a
conversation with him about like what
that looks like and is there a sense
that the team lost some of that edge the
last couple years?
>> Yeah, I know Dan's talked about it, you
know, I think Brad mentioned it in one
of his press conferences. I think you
know one of as I said earlier, one of
the advantages of going through a year
where you were disappointed is it does
force you to think about things. Um and
I think you know we we kind of came
through a period and Dan and I have
talked about it where you know you were
building this the right way. You draft
players, you know, you develop them, we
start to have success, they become
stars. And how do you manage a team now
that's successful and has a bunch of
stars on it versus a team that was, you
know, you know, Aman Ron State Brown
drafted in the fourth round throw and
upset all these receivers were taken
ahead of him. How do you go back and you
can't recreate that situation, but how
do you come up with ideas to create a
situation where we have the same kind of
hunger? And I think the fact that we
missed the playoffs, didn't win the
division, you know, in itself create
some of that. And I think, you know,
some of the things that we're looking at
internally and injuries and how we
practice um all those things I think
will get us back on the right path.
>> The um injuries and I said you're
looking at everything you said at twice
now. Like does that involve like
bringing in like outside consultation?
Like do you do you extend that to to
really dive deep into those things
>> for certain types of injuries? Uh you
know fish breer has reached out to
experts in every kind of you know muscle
and training and everything. So, we're
not leaving any stone unturned. Um, and
I don't think any team can have 0%
injuries, but if we can find, you know,
a magic bullet here or there to
eliminate or get a player back faster
because it's both, you know, how injured
are they and how quickly can they get
back on the field. Um, and I think, you
know, the other thing is, you know, just
preparing for it with more depth as much
as possible because they're going to
happen. Um, you know, last year we went
into the season, nobody would have
expected that we'd be worrying about
safety at the end of the year with, you
know, two allp pro safeties, but
unfortunately it happened and you have
to be prepared for it. So, it's a
combination of all those things. Um, and
I think that's one of the advantages of
having so many picks on Saturday is you
have a chance to like get some back
roster guys and hopefully hit on a few
of them and you develop those guys into
the next wave of backups and maybe
starters.
>> Natural grass stuff kind of stall. Yeah,
it was interesting we looked at today um
in terms of across the league, you know,
natural grass and artificial turf, there
is no discernable difference in
injuries. Um and there's even within,
you know, natural grass fields, you
know, some that are good, some that
aren't good. And within artificial turf,
some that are good and some are less
good. Um we stay on top of ours. We
apply all the testing that the league
expects. you know, we'll probably be
changing out the field in a year or two
to kind of keep it current with the most
current technology. Um, unfortunately
with the dome stadium, grass becomes
virtually impossible. Um, so we have to
do the best we can with the artificial
turf technology that's out there.
>> Say any electrical substation theories
or anything like that.
>> What do you have any?
>> No, sort of nature happened. Yeah,
>> conspiracy theorists out there on the
49ers.
>> What are your uh plans for retirement?
>> Well, when I get there, I'll have more
specific plans because it's going to be
a few months, but um we we'll move to
Florida, you know, pretty much
full-time. We have a place in Palm Beach
and I'm on a couple of boards, maybe add
a couple um see our kids and grandkids
more. Um I'll definitely be a Lions fan
for life. tend to come to all the home
games and maybe some of the road games.
Um, and then just kind of, you know,
enjoy some time that I've been taking
away from my family with my family.
>> So, then, uh, I'm curious just with the
success that you guys have had over the
last couple years, what kind of like
unique opportunities has that brought
for the team that maybe you weren't
expecting, you know, outside of just a
lot of inter?
>> Yeah, it's an interesting question. I do
think, you know, the the brand of the
team is, you know, in a completely
different place than it was a couple
years ago. Um, some of that's the team
success. I think some of that's the
personalities we have on the team. Um,
obviously the winning helps. Uh, prime
time games help. Um, hard knocks helped.
Um, so I think you know the the brand,
you know, we are in a position where now
these meetings are very different for me
where people are asking our advice on
how to do some of the things we've done
versus us trying to figure out how to do
what other teams have done. Um, but it
all starts with having a great football
team. And if you don't have a
competitive product that the fans
believe in and have hope that you can
win, uh, everything else is really,
really hard. Um, so I think we've got
that side right and set and hopefully we
can continue to build on it. What do you
think you're going to miss the most
>> besides this?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> you can come back.
>> Yeah, I know. Well,
>> you got the Sonoma house.
>> Yeah.
>> It's worrisome that you guys know where
my houses are, but
>> our jobs.
>> Um,
touche. Um, you know, I think, you know,
you'll you'll miss the camaraderie. You
know, I was talking about, you know, you
know, you miss flying away on the team
playing and, you know, having dinner the
night before with our our group and
being in the locker room after when
there's nothing, you know, that can kind
of compare to that. Um um and that's the
kind of stuff that most the fans don't
really see a lot of. I mean, obviously
show the videos of the locker room, but
that's kind of a small version of what
really goes on. Um and I have told Dan
when we win the Super Bowl, I expect a
ring. So, um hopefully that happens uh
in the next couple years and I don't
miss out on that. But, uh you'll you'll
miss the people you work with and the
people you're close to and you know the
coaching staff and Dan and Brad really
haven't worked for anybody other than
than me. So, I'll miss that and um but
it's still the right time for me.
>> You're going to get one of the tier two
rings though. You don't get the the top
top one. I think
>> you think you do you have a do you have
a vote on this?
>> I think so.
>> I think when you're out you're out.
Good.
>> All right. I'll
>> just You guys have been revamping the
the facility kind of piece by
>> I'm ignoring him though.
>> Um what's next on the horizon from that?
>> Uh nothing specifically. Um but you
know, we have some plans that we've kind
of been mothballing until we got this
375 project figured out. Uh but now that
we know that we're not going to have a
three to five year disruption of how
people get to the stadium, uh there's
some things that we're going to bring
back out. Um you know, the inside of the
stadium. I think remains, you know,
awesome. The environment's awesome. Uh
we struggle with a lot of the back of
the house stuff, only having, you know,
a tunnel on one, you know, corner, only
having half of back of house, uh which
is, I think, eventually going to prevent
us from getting some big events. I mean,
we have the final four coming, but you
know, I think to get another final four,
we're going to have to have some back of
house improvements. Um, so those are the
kind of things we're looking at. And
then, you know, thinking about, you
know, the fan experience of the future.
You know, how many clubs do you have?
How many GA seats do you have? How many
suites do you have? And you have to kind
of be thinking, you know, long term. I
would have never thought six, seven
years ago that we needed to add suites,
but we've added sweets the last couple
years. Um, so, you know, you have to be
nimble enough to kind of think about
where the the fan experience is. But,
um, there's some things that we're we're
looking at probably in the next couple
years, they may come to life, but
nothing immediately.
>> Probably safe to assume you guys will be
a hot front ticket again next year.
>> Based upon my discussions with Mike
North, I think so. Yeah. I mean, because
he's pushing back on a lot of my
requests, including the Thursday
Thursday thing. So, I think that there's
still a lot of interest in the Lions
despite, you know, last year's, you
know, little disappointment. Um, and I I
think there's probably an expectation
that we're going to bounce back and be
really competitive next year. So, I
would assume yes. Yeah.